They were searching for proof... they found it.
Grave Encounters is a thriller, horror film directed by Stuart Ortiz.
A crew from a paranormal reality television show lock
themselves in a haunted psychiatric hospital.
They search for evidence of paranormal activity as they shoot
what ends up becoming their final episode.
Lance Preston, played by Sean Rogerson.
Sasha Parker, played by Ashleigh Gryzko.
T.C. Gibson, played by Merwin Mondesir.
Houston Gray, played by Mackenzie Gray.
Matt White, played by Juan Riedinger.
Dr. Arthur Friedkin, played by Arthur Corber.
Grave Encounters is a 2011 Canadian found footage supernatural horror
film written and directed by the Vicious Brothers.
The film stars Sean Rogerson, Ashleigh Gryzko, Merwin Mondesir, Mackenzie Gray, and Juan Riedinger as the crew of a successful paranormal reality television series who lock
themselves in a supposedly haunted psychiatric hospital to search for evidence of paranormal activity as they shoot what ends up becoming the series' final episode.
Grave Encounters premiered on April 22, 2011, at the Tribeca Film Festival and was released through video on
demand, with a simultaneous limited theatrical release in the United States, on August 25, 2011.
It was a commercial success, grossing over $5 million against a
$120,000 budget, and received mixed reviews from critics.
The film has garnered a cult following since its
release, with a sequel released in 2012.
The film explores themes of haunting, insane asylum,
paranormal, psychiatric hospital, ghost hunting.
The tone is dark and intense.